certifiedhosting.com 2010-11-21

# Certified Hosting - Privacy Policy

Certified Hosting is committed to protecting your privacy. The following information is designed to help you understand how we collect, use, disseminate and safeguard the information you provide to us while using our web site (located at: www.certifiedhosting.com) or our Hosting services. By accessing and using our web site and Hosting services, you signify your assent to the certified hosting Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with our information practices, please choose another Hosting company for your Hosting services. As provided below, we reserve the right, at our discretion, to change, add or remove portions of this policy at any time by posting such changes to our Homepage.

This privacy policy applies only to the privacy practices for www.certifiedhosting.com. It does not apply to third party sites for which certified hosting provides Hosting services. If you are interested in the privacy practices of the sites hosted by certified hosting, or if you have any other comments, suggestions, or complaints regarding those third party sites, you should contact the site(s) in question directly. Certified Hosting is not responsible for the privacy practices or other business practices of the sites for which it provides Hosting services.

**Information Collection and Use**  
certified hosting is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement. certified hosting collects information from our users at several different points on our website.

**Registration and Order Forms**  
In order to sign-up for our Hosting services, a user must either complete the registration and order form on-line, or send us this information via facsimile transmission or regular mail. During registration, a user is required to give their contact information (such as name, phone number, fax number, and e-mail address) and certain financial information (like credit card number, expiration date, and/or checking account number). This information is used to set-up and maintain an account, process payments, provide hosting services, and if we have trouble processing an order or otherwise need to contact a user, the contact information is used to get in touch with the user.

**Cookies**  
A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user’s hard drive containing information about the user. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site. Once the user closes their browser, the cookie simply terminates. For instance, by setting a cookie on our site, the user would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on our site. If a user rejects the cookie, they may still use certain portions of our site, although other portions may not be accessible.

While we do not currently use cookies on our site, we may use cookies in the future in order to expand our service offerings and provide better service to our users. Some of our business partners may use cookies on our site (for example, advertisers). However, we have no access to or control over these cookies.

**Log Files**  
Our server software collects and records IP addresses, referring URLs, OS and browser types, and records what files are downloaded by end users of the sites hosted by us. We use this information to analyze trends, administer the sites, track user movements through our site and the sites hosted by us, and to gather broad demographic information for aggregate use (collectively, “Web Statistics”). We use the Web Statistics to enhance our Hosting services, monitor and improve our network, and to provide the sites hosted by us with usage information.

**Sharing**  
We may share aggregated demographic information with our hosted sites and with our sponsors. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person. We may also use an outside company or companies to process payments. From time to time, we may contract with another party to provide certain specific services to our users.

We currently do not sell or otherwise make available personally identifiable information about our users or Web Statistics to third parties. Nevertheless, we reserve the right to make such information available to third parties in the future in order to enhance our services.

**Law Enforcement**  
We will cooperate with law enforcement authorities, private-party litigants, and others seeking information about our end users and the sites hosted by us to the extent required by applicable law. We will also notify the appropriate authorities if we suspect that any of our users or any of the users of the sites hosted by us are engaged in illegal activities, such as obscenity or child pornography.

**Links**  
This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that certified hosting is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information.

**Security**  
We agree to use commercially reasonable efforts to protect the information you have provided to us from unauthorized access by using encryption and other security measures. We encourage you to contact us if you are interested in learning more about our security measures.  
Third Party Sources of Information

From time to time and in order to enhance our services, we may supplement the information we receive from you with information we obtain from third party sources.

**Special Offers**  
We send all new users a welcome e-mail to verify password and username. Established members will occasionally receive information on new products, services, special deals, and a newsletter. Out of respect for the privacy of our users, we present the option to not receive these periodic communications.

**Children**  
We do not offer our Hosting services to children. We do not target children for our hosting services, nor do we solicit data, or knowingly collect personally identifiable information from them. We encourage parents and legal guardians to spend time online with their children and to participate in the interactive activities offered on the sites their children visit.

**Service Updates**  
From time to time, we may send users site and service announcement updates (such as information about emergency and planned downtimes). You are not permitted to un-subscribe to these notices because they may contain important information about the Hosting services.

**Correction/Updating Personal Information**  
If a user’s personally identifiable information changes (such as phone number or a credit card number), or if a user no longer desires our service, you may contact us to correct or update this information.

**Choice/Opt-out**  
Users who no longer wish to receive promotional materials may opt-out of receiving these communications by contacting us.

**Notification of Changes**  
We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time by posting such changes to our Homepage. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will become effective upon posting to the Homepage. If you use our Hosting services, you are required to periodically check our Privacy Policy for any changes. If you continue to use our Hosting services after we have changed our Privacy Policy, you manifest your assent to the changes to our Privacy Policy.

If we decide to use your personally identifiable information in a manner materially different from that stated in the Privacy Policy at the time that such information was collected, we will attempt to notify you of such changes. You agree that if we send you an e-mail to the e-mail address reflected in our records, such e-mail will constitute acceptable notice to you of the change in our policy. The notice will provide you with an opportunity to “opt-out” so that we may not use your personally identifiable information in a manner which is different from the manner described at the time that you provided us with such information. If you do not affirmatively “opt-out” pursuant to the instructions provided to you in the notice, them you agree that we may use your personally identifiable information in the manner described in the notice.

**Contact Information**  
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, or if you otherwise need to contact us regarding your personally identifiable information, please contact us by sending an e-mail to: hostmaster@certified hosting.com. Please provide us with your password, user name and account number so we can service you quicker.

You may also contact by telephone at: 800.547.9995, or you may send us a facsimile at: 909.954.9570

Last Revised 02/25/09   
Certified Hosting Solutions Confidential & Proprietary
